<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>

    <!--==================== Plants: Extra Info ====================-->

    <SZAB_PlantHarvestSeasonInfo>Harvestable during: {0}.</SZAB_PlantHarvestSeasonInfo>
    <SZAB_PlantHarvestTimeInfo>Harvestable between: {0} hrs - {1} hrs.</SZAB_PlantHarvestTimeInfo>
    <SZAB_PlantGlowerInfo>Glows between: {0} hrs - {1} hrs.</SZAB_PlantGlowerInfo>
    <SZAB_PlantNasticHarmfulInfo>Reactive: radius ({0} cells), damage ({1})</SZAB_PlantNasticHarmfulInfo>
    <SZAB_PlantNasticHarmfulInfo_ExThreshold>Explosive growth threshold: {0}%</SZAB_PlantNasticHarmfulInfo_ExThreshold>
    <SZAB_PlantNasticHediffGiverInfo>Reactive: radius ({0} cells), hediff ({1})</SZAB_PlantNasticHediffGiverInfo>
    <SZAB_PlantNasticHarmfulInfo_HeThreshold>Hediff giver growth threshold: {0}%, chance {1}%</SZAB_PlantNasticHarmfulInfo_HeThreshold>

    <!--==================== Letters ====================-->

    <SZAB_LetterLabelDesertBloom>Desert bloom</SZAB_LetterLabelDesertBloom>
    <SZAB_LetterDesertBloom>An extraordinarily rare weather phenomenon has swept across the dunes, bringing with it life-giving rains. As the raindrops hit the parched ground, the elusive Sandblossoms and other rarely-seen flora begin to bloom in abundance, covering the landscape. Make haste to gather any valuable resources as these rare plants tend to have a short lifespan without plentiful water supplies.</SZAB_LetterDesertBloom>

    <SZAB_LetterLabelCrystallizing>Colonist crystallizing</SZAB_LetterLabelCrystallizing>
    <SZAB_LetterCrystallizing>{0} has been exposed to an aggressive form of living crystal parasites. These microscopic glass-like invaders will begin attacking {0_possessive} capillaries and immune system. Early treatment is essential here! Once {0_possessive} body has been weakened enough the parasites will spread to more vital regions of the body as they feed on {0_possessive} soul. Upon full synthesis with the host body and once all nutrients have been depleted, {0} will be obliterated and a magnificent red crystal will arise from the pooling blood.</SZAB_LetterCrystallizing>

    <SZAB_LetterLabelCrystallized>Colonist crystallized</SZAB_LetterLabelCrystallized>
    <SZAB_LetterCrystallized>{0} has perished as a result of microscopic parasites released from a colossal crystal. Colonists will mourn {0_possessive} death, and they will forever be remembered in crimson fervor.</SZAB_LetterCrystallized>

    <!--==================== Mod Settings ====================-->

    <SZAB_ModName>Alien Biomes</SZAB_ModName>

    <SZAB_SettingPlantGlow>Show glow effects.</SZAB_SettingPlantGlow>
    <SZAB_SettingPlantGlowDesc>Many plants in Alien Biomes glow at various times of the day. This may significantly improve performance on large maps if turned off, depending on hardware, map size, and number of plants able to glow.</SZAB_SettingPlantGlowDesc>
    
    <SZAB_SettingShowTerrainDebris>Show terrain debris.</SZAB_SettingShowTerrainDebris>
    <SZAB_SettingShowTerrainDebrisDesc>If unchecked, vanilla terrain-related debris (sand and soil smears) will not be generated on map creation.</SZAB_SettingShowTerrainDebrisDesc>

    <SZAB_SettingCompEffectSounds>Allow plants to emit ambient sounds.</SZAB_SettingCompEffectSounds>
    <SZAB_SettingCompEffectSoundsDesc>Certain plants added by Alien Biomes have unique behaviors and some emit short ambient queues when pawns are nearby or are walking through them. Turn this off if you prefer total silence and dislike nature.</SZAB_SettingCompEffectSoundsDesc>

    <SZAB_SettingPlantSFXChance>Volume: {0}%</SZAB_SettingPlantSFXChance>
    <SZAB_SettingPlantSFXChanceDesc>Adjust the slider to either increase or decreases the chance a plants' touch reactive sound plays every time a valid pawn gets close enough to the plant.\n\nA value of 0 means the sound will never play.</SZAB_SettingPlantSFXChanceDesc>
    
    <SZAB_SettingCrystallizing>Allow colonists to be crystallized in the Crystalline Flats.</SZAB_SettingCrystallizing>
    <SZAB_SettingCrystallizingDesc>This can make for some challenging gameplay but is also a fair challenge. Pawns afflicted with the crystallizing hediff will eventually die and be replaced by a magnificent red crystal.</SZAB_SettingCrystallizingDesc>
    
</LanguageData>